Guide to the National Education Association-Conventions records, 1857-1998 NEA1008.RG
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
National Education Association-Conferences and Conventions
Bulk, 1970-1996 1857-1998
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
National Education Association of the United States
NEA1008.RG
113.5 Linear Feet
Historical Note
The National Education Association (NEA) is the largest professional organization and largest labor union in the United States, representing public school teachers and other support personnel, faculty and staffers at colleges and universities, retired educators, and college students preparing to become teachers. In 2010, the NEA had 3.2 million members and is located in Washington, D.C. The group holds a congressional charter under Title 36 of the United States Code granted in 1906.
The NEA describes itself as a professional employee organization. The mission of the National Education Association is "to advocate for education professionals and to unite our members and the nation to fulfill the promise of public education to prepare every student to succeed in a diverse and interdependent world."
The NEA is a volunteer-based organization that relies upon its members to perform much of the Association's work. The members are supported by staff at the local, state, and national levels with the stated goal of "building great public schools for every student."
In 1857, Thomas W. Valentine, president of the New York State Teachers Association, issued a nation-wide invitation to teachers to unite in Philadelphia behind a common voice for America's growing public school system. After the meeting, the National Teachers Association (NTA) was formed with a membership of about 100. Minority educators were allowed to join at the start, but women were not allowed to join until 1866.
In 1870, the NTA merged with the American Normal School Association, the National Association of School Superintendents, and the Central College Association renaming itself the National Education Association. For the first 100 years of its existence, the NEA was controlled by administrators, and worked to further the interests of the "education profession" as a whole.
In the 1960's, after the first passage of a collective bargaining law for public employees, the NEA adopted union activities in addition to its operations as a professional association.
The NEA merged with the American Teachers Association (ATA), formerly the National Association of Teachers in Colored Schools (NATCS) in 1966.
In 1998, a proposed merger with the American Federation of Teachers (AFT) failed when it was rejected by NEA's Representative Assembly. Several NEA state affiliates have merged with their AFT counterparts, effectively forming a single association.
Over the years, the NEA has been a leader in national education reform and improvement movements. It has worked to improve the education provided to American school children through lobbying and campaigning on the local and national level as well as by promoting strong teacher education programs and continuous professional assessment and development.
Historical Note
NEA's Convention takes place anuually, during June or July. Various committees, constituencies, caucuses, leadership groups, and delegates from state and local affiliates gather in order to set policy and chart the direction of NEA business. The location of the meeting is different every year. The Representative Assembly takes place during the final four days of the Annual Meeting.
The NEA also has many other conferences and meetings such as the Regional Leadership Conference, Minority Leadership Training Seminars, Women's Leadership Training Program, and Higher Education Conference to name a few.
Scope and Contents
Subseries contains materials created by the Office of Convention and Conference Management (later Conferences and Facilities Management). The files include materials detailing the planning and management of the annual conventions, memoranda, hotel and convention center information, meeting arrangements, convention delegate packets, reports on conventions, and news coverage of later annual meetings.
These records provide excellent insight into the management of hosting conventions and conferences. Details on hotels, floor plans, and arrangements for speakers are all included to offer a comprehensive look at the planning of these events.
Arrangement note
The collection is organized into roughly alphabetical series based upon the NEA's organization. Records have been allocated largely to their offices of origin and reflect the work done within the offices, departments, divisions and units. Due to the immense size of the collection and the constraints placed upon the finding aid by the archival management system utilized by George Washington University, the collection was further divided up into parts.
Organized into 2 series: Conventions and Conferences; Convention Proceedings User Aids.
Separated Materials note
Several bound volumes were removed from the collection and placed on the shelves. The volumes include: The
"Addresses and Proceedings" from 1873-1993 (missing 1878, 1922, 1992); "Indexes" for 1871-1897 and 1871-1906; "Minutes of the Board of Directors and Executive Committee" (1973-1993); "Addresses and Proceedings of the NEA" (1871-1872); "Addresses and Journal of Proceedings of the American Normal School and the National Teachers' Associations", 1870 (3 copies); "National Teachers' Association, National Superintendents' Association, American Normal School Association", 1868; "Proceedings of the National Teachers' Association", (1857-1860, 1863-1866, 1868-1870(2 copies of each)).
Teachers; Education -- United States -- History; Labor unions; Labor unions -- United States -- History -- 20th century
- Conventions and Conferences, Bulk, 1970-1996 1858-1998; 1970-1996; Series 1; National Education Association of the United States. Meeting.; 85 Linear Feet
  Arrangement note
  Arranged by annual convention year for the convention specific files, and followed by general files arranged alphabetically by title, and chronologically within the same title.
  Separated Materials note
  Several bound volumes were removed from the collection and placed on the shelves. The volumes include: The
  "Addresses and Proceedings" from 1873-1993 (missing 1878, 1922, 1992); "Indexes" for 1871-1897 and 1871-1906; "Minutes of the Board of Directors and Executive Committee" (1973-1993); "Addresses and Proceedings of the NEA" (1871-1872); "Addresses and Journal of Proceedings of the American Normal School and the National Teachers' Associations", 1870 (3 copies); "National Teachers' Association, National Superintendents' Association, American Normal School Association", 1868; "Proceedings of the National Teachers' Association", (1857-1860, 1863-1866, 1868-1870(2 copies of each)).
  Biographical/Historical note
  NEA's Convention takes place anuually, during June or July. Various committees, constituencies, caucuses, leadership groups, and delegates from state and local affiliates gather in order to set policy and chart the direction of NEA business. The location of the meeting is different every year. The Representative Assembly takes place during the final four days of the Annual Meeting.
  The NEA also has many other conferences and meetings such as the Regional Leadership Conference, Minority Leadership Training Seminars, Women's Leadership Training Program, and Higher Education Conference to name a few.
  Scope and Contents note
  Subseries contains materials created by the Office of Convention and Conference Management (later Conferences and Facilities Management) as well as material from conventions. The files include materials detailing the planning and management of the annual conventions, memoranda, hotel and convention center information, meeting arrangements, convention delegate packets, reports on conventions, and news coverage of later annual meetings. There are also programs and visitor's guides for select convention and convention cities.
  These records provide excellent insight into the management of hosting conventions and conferences. Details on hotels, floor plans, and arrangements for speakers are all included to offer a comprehensive look at the planning of these events.
  - 8th Annual Salute to Excellence in Education Gala, 2002; Series 1 (Box 4781, Folder 15)
  - 19th Annual Conference Collective Bargaining in Higher Education: Leadership in Uncertain Times, March 1991; series 1 (Box 4418, Folder 18)
  - 109th Annual Meeting, June 26-July 2, 1971; Series 1 (Box 4737, Folder 1)
  - 110th Annual Meeting- Summer of 72, June 24-30, 1972; Series 1 (Box 4737, Folder 2)
  - 111th Annual Meeting, June 29-July 6, 1973; Series 1 (Box 4737, Folder 3)
  - 112th Annual Meeting- Crisis in Confidence 1974: Challenge for the Classroom, June 28-July 3, 1974; Series 1 (Box 4737, Folder 4)
  - 113th Annual Meeting- Educational Strategies During an Economic Crisis, July 3-8, 1975; Series 1 (Box 4737, Folder 5)
  - 114th Annual Meeting- America's Third Century: The Teacher's Unfinished Agenda, June 25-July 1, 1976; Series 1 (Box 4737, Folder 6)
  - 115th Annual Meeting- Public Education: More than Survival, July1-July 6, 1977; Series 1 (Box 4737, Folder 7)
  - 116th Annual Meeting- United We Decide. United We Act, July 1-6, 1978; Series 1 (Box 4737, Folder 8)
  - 117th Annual Meeting- We Teach the Children, June 30-July 5, 1970; Series 1 (Box 4737, Folder 9)
  - 120th Annual Meeting- Political Power for Educational Excellence, July 1-6, 1982; Series 1 (Box 4737, Folder 10)
  - 122th Annual Meeting- Excellence and Equity in Education, June 29, 1984; Series 1 (Box 4737, Folder 11)
  - The 15th International Conference on Critical Thinking & Educational Reform, 1995 July 30 - August 2; Series 1 (Box 4998, Folder 5)
  - The 17th International Conference on Critical Thinking & Educational Reform, 1997 August 3-6; Series 1 (Box 4998, Folder 6)
  - 1927 Convention - The Pageant Session - Forest Trails, July 6, 1927; Series 1 (Box 3514, Folder 1)
  - 1951-San Francisco, CA, Series 1 (Box 1342, Folder 1)
  - 1958 NEA Convention Craker Barrel Session, series 1 (Box 4230, Folder 8)
  - 1960-Los Angeles, CA-Information Bulletin, Series 1 (Box 1342, Folder 2)
  - 1961 Staff Conference: Leadership Challenge of the 60's, ca. 1961; series 1 (Box 4253, Folder 7)
  - 1963 Conference on Driver Education Pamphlet, November 1963; series 1 (Box 4398, Folder 26)
  - 1966-Miami Beach, FL, Series 1 (Box 1342, Folder 3)
  - 1967-Minneapolis, MN [file 1/2], Series 1 (Box 1342, Folder 4)
  - 1967-Minneapolis, MN [file 2/2], Series 1 (Box 1342, Folder 5)
  - 1968-Dallas, TX, Series 1 (Box 1342, Folder 6)
  - 1969 Conference Pamphlet ASCD, series 1 (Box 4398, Folder 27)
  - 1969-Philadelphia, PA, Series 1 (Box 1342, Folder 7)
  - 1969 NEA Convention Report, Series 1 (Box 4074, Folder 5)
  - 1970-San Francisco, CA, Series 1 (Box 1342, Folder 8)
  - 1970 Annual Convention - San Francisco, series 1 (Box 4379, Folder 6)
  - 1971 Annual Meeting - Detroit, 1970; series 1 (Box 4379, Folder 7)
  - 1971-Detroit, MI, Series 1 (Box 1343, Folder 1)
  - 1972-Atlantic City, NJ [file 1/7], Series 1 (Box 1343, Folder 2)
  - 1972-Atlantic City, NJ [file 2/7], Series 1 (Box 1343, Folder 3)
  - 1972-Atlantic City, NJ [file 3/7], Series 1 (Box 1343, Folder 4)
  - 1972-Atlantic City, NJ [file 4/7], Series 1 (Box 1344, Folder 1)
  - 1972-Atlantic City, NJ [file 5/7], Series 1 (Box 1344, Folder 2)
  - 1972-Atlantic City, NJ [file 6/7], Series 1 (Box 1344, Folder 3)
  - 1972-Atlantic City, NJ [file 7/7], Series 1 (Box 1344, Folder 4)
  - 1973-Portland, OR [file 1/6], Series 1 (Box 1344, Folder 5)
  - 1973-Portland, OR [file 2/6], Series 1 (Box 1344, Folder 6)
  - 1973-Portland, OR [file 3/6], Series 1 (Box 1345, Folder 1)
  - 1973-Portland, OR [file 4/6], Series 1 (Box 1345, Folder 2)
  - 1973-Portland, OR [file 5/6], Series 1 (Box 1345, Folder 3)
  - 1973-Portland, OR [file 6/6], Series 1 (Box 1345, Folder 4)
  - 1973-Portland, OR-Administration of Conference, Series 1 (Box 1345, Folder 5)
  - 1973-Portland, OR-Afternoon Content Suggestions, Series 1 (Box 1345, Folder 6)
  - 1973-Portland, OR-Agreements with Staff Implementation, Series 1 (Box 1345, Folder 7)
  - 1973-Portland, OR-Background Statement of Objectives, Series 1 (Box 1345, Folder 8)
  - 1973-Portland, OR-Convention Report, Series 1 (Box 1345, Folder 9)
  - 1973-Portland, OR-Morning Content Suggestions, Series 1 (Box 1346, Folder 1)
  - 1973-Portland, OR-Planning Meetings, Officers, and Staff, Series 1 (Box 1346, Folder 2)
  - 1973-Portland, OR-Policy of Conference, Series 1 (Box 1346, Folder 3)
  - 1974-Chicago, IL [file 1/6], Series 1 (Box 1346, Folder 4)
  - 1974-Chicago, IL [file 2/6], Series 1 (Box 1346, Folder 5)
  - 1974-Chicago, IL [file 3/6], Series 1 (Box 1346, Folder 6)
  - 1974-Chicago, IL [file 4/6], Series 1 (Box 1346, Folder 7)
  - 1974-Chicago, IL [file 5/6], Series 1 (Box 1347, Folder 1)
  - 1974-Chicago, IL [file 6/6], Series 1 (Box 1347, Folder 2)
  - 1974-Chicago, IL-Critical Issues, 1973-1974; Series 1 (Box 1347, Folder 3)
  - 1974-Chicago, IL-Critical Issues-Program and Speeches, 1971-1973; Series 1 (Box 1347, Folder 4)
  - 1974-Chicago, IL-Quarterly Product Summary, Series 1 (Box 1347, Folder 5)
  - 1975-Los Angeles, CA [file 1/16], Series 1 (Box 1348, Folder 1)
  - 1975-Los Angeles, CA [file 2/16], Series 1 (Box 1348, Folder 2)
  - 1975-Los Angeles, CA [file 3/16], Series 1 (Box 1348, Folder 3)
  - 1975-Los Angeles, CA [file 4/16], Series 1 (Box 1348, Folder 4)
  - 1975-Los Angeles, CA [file 5/16], Series 1 (Box 1348, Folder 5)
  - 1975-Los Angeles, CA [file 6/16], Series 1 (Box 1349, Folder 1)
  - 1975-Los Angeles, CA [file 7/16], Series 1 (Box 1349, Folder 2)
  - 1975-Los Angeles, CA [file 8/16], Series 1 (Box 1349, Folder 3)
  - 1975-Los Angeles, CA [file 9/16], Series 1 (Box 1349, Folder 4)
  - 1975-Los Angeles, CA [file 10/16], Series 1 (Box 1349, Folder 5)
  - 1975-Los Angeles, CA [file 11/16], Series 1 (Box 1350, Folder 1)
  - 1975-Los Angeles, CA [file 12/16], Series 1 (Box 1350, Folder 2)
  - 1975-Los Angeles, CA [file 13/16], Series 1 (Box 1350, Folder 3)
  - 1975-Los Angeles, CA [file 14/16], Series 1 (Box 1350, Folder 4)
  - 1975-Los Angeles, CA [file 15/16], Series 1 (Box 1350, Folder 5)
  - 1975-Los Angeles, CA [file 16/16], Series 1 (Box 1350, Folder 6)
  - 1975-Los Angeles, CA-Convention Budget Analysis, 1974-1975; Series 1 (Box 1351, Folder 1)
  - 1975-Los Angeles, CA-Critical Issues, 1974-1975; Series 1 (Box 1351, Folder 2)
  - 1975-Los Angeles, CA-Laverne College, 1975-1976; Series 1 (Box 1351, Folder 3)
  - 1975-Los Angeles, CA-Program, Series 1 (Box 1351, Folder 4)
  - 1976-Miami, FL [file 1/8], Series 1 (Box 1351, Folder 5)
  - 1976-Miami, FL [file 2/8], Series 1 (Box 1351, Folder 6)
  - 1976-Miami, FL [file 3/8], Series 1 (Box 1351, Folder 7)
  - 1976-Miami, FL [file 4/8], Series 1 (Box 1352, Folder 1)
  - 1976-Miami, FL [file 5/8], Series 1 (Box 1352, Folder 2)
  - 1976-Miami, FL [file 6/8], Series 1 (Box 1352, Folder 3)
  - 1976-Miami, FL [file 7/8], Series 1 (Box 1352, Folder 4)
  - 1976-Miami, FL [file 8/8], Series 1 (Box 1353, Folder 1)
  - 1976-Miami, FL-Co-Ex Services Inc., Series 1 (Box 1353, Folder 2)
  - 1976-Miami, FL-OCCM Budget, 1975-1976; Series 1 (Box 1353, Folder 3)
  - 1976-Miami, FL-Program, Series 1 (Box 1353, Folder 4)
  - 1977-Minneapolis, MN [file 1/6], Series 1 (Box 1353, Folder 5)
  - 1977-Minneapolis, MN [file 2/6], Series 1 (Box 1353, Folder 6)
  - 1977-Minneapolis, MN [file 3/6], Series 1 (Box 1353, Folder 7)
  - 1977-Minneapolis, MN [file 4/6], Series 1 (Box 1354, Folder 1)
  - 1977-Minneapolis, MN [file 5/6], Series 1 (Box 1354, Folder 2)
  - 1977-Minneapolis, MN [file 6/6], Series 1 (Box 1354, Folder 3)
  - 1977-Minneapolis, MN-Program, Series 1 (Box 1354, Folder 4)
  - 1977-Minneapolis, MN-Yates Progress Report and Personnel, 1976-1977; Series 1 (Box 1354, Folder 5)
  - 1978-Dallas, TX [file 1/10], Series 1 (Box 1355, Folder 1)
  - 1978-Dallas, TX [file 2/10], Series 1 (Box 1355, Folder 2)
  - 1978-Dallas, TX [file 3/10], Series 1 (Box 1355, Folder 3)
  - 1978-Dallas, TX [file 4/10], Series 1 (Box 1355, Folder 4)
  - 1978-Dallas, TX [file 5/10], Series 1 (Box 1356, Folder 1)
  - 1978-Dallas, TX [file 6/10], Series 1 (Box 1356, Folder 2)
  - 1978-Dallas, TX [file 7/10], Series 1 (Box 1356, Folder 3)
  - 1978-Dallas, TX [file 8/10], Series 1 (Box 1356, Folder 4)
  - 1978-Dallas, TX [file 9/10], Series 1 (Box 1357, Folder 1)
  - 1978-Dallas, TX [file 10/10], Series 1 (Box 1357, Folder 2)
  - 1978-Dallas, TX-Committee on Racism, Series 1 (Box 1357, Folder 3)
  - 1978-Dallas, TX-National Rifle Association, Series 1 (Box 1357, Folder 4)
  - 1978-Dallas, TX-Program, Series 1 (Box 1357, Folder 5)
  - 1979-Detroit, MI [file 1/18], Series 1 (Box 1357, Folder 6)
  - 1979-Detroit, MI [file 2/18], Series 1 (Box 1357, Folder 7)
  - 1979-Detroit, MI [file 3/18], Series 1 (Box 1358, Folder 1)
  - 1979-Detroit, MI [file 4/18], Series 1 (Box 1358, Folder 2)
  - 1979-Detroit, MI [file 5/18], Series 1 (Box 1358, Folder 3)
  - 1979-Detroit, MI [file 6/18], Series 1 (Box 1358, Folder 4)
  - 1979-Detroit, MI [file 7/18], Series 1 (Box 1359, Folder 1)
  - 1979-Detroit, MI [file 8/18], Series 1 (Box 1359, Folder 2)
  - 1979-Detroit, MI [file 9/18], Series 1 (Box 1359, Folder 3)
  - 1979-Detroit, MI [file 10/18], Series 1 (Box 1359, Folder 4)
  - 1979-Detroit, MI [file 11/18], Series 1 (Box 1359, Folder 5)
  - 1979-Detroit, MI [file 12/18], Series 1 (Box 1360, Folder 1)
  - 1979-Detroit, MI [file 13/18], Series 1 (Box 1360, Folder 2)
  - 1979-Detroit, MI [file 14/18], Series 1 (Box 1360, Folder 3)
  - 1979-Detroit, MI [file 15/18], Series 1 (Box 1360, Folder 4)
  - 1979-Detroit, MI [file 16/18], Series 1 (Box 1360, Folder 5)
  - 1979-Detroit, MI [file 17/18], Series 1 (Box 1361, Folder 1)
  - 1979-Detroit, MI [file 18/18], Series 1 (Box 1361, Folder 2)
  - 1979-Detroit, MI-Program, Series 1 (Box 1361, Folder 3)
  - 1979-Detroit, MI-Camping, Series 1 (Box 1361, Folder 4)
  - 1979-Detroit, MI-Committee Against Racism, Series 1 (Box 1361, Folder 5)
  - 1979-Detroit, MI-Friendship Night, Series 1 (Box 1361, Folder 6)
  - 1979-Detroit, MI-NRA Letters, Series 1 (Box 1361, Folder 7)
  - 1980-Los Angeles, CA [file 1/19], Series 1 (Box 1362, Folder 1)
  - 1980-Los Angeles, CA [file 2/19], Series 1 (Box 1362, Folder 2)
  - 1980-Los Angeles, CA [file 3/19], Series 1 (Box 1362, Folder 3)
  - 1980-Los Angeles, CA [file 4/19], Series 1 (Box 1362, Folder 4)
  - 1980-Los Angeles, CA [file 5/19], Series 1 (Box 1362, Folder 5)
  - 1980-Los Angeles, CA [file 6/19], Series 1 (Box 1363, Folder 1)
  - 1980-Los Angeles, CA [file 7/19], Series 1 (Box 1363, Folder 2)
  - 1980-Los Angeles, CA [file 8/19], Series 1 (Box 1363, Folder 3)
  - 1980-Los Angeles, CA [file 9/19], Series 1 (Box 1363, Folder 4)
  - 1980-Los Angeles, CA [file 10/19], Series 1 (Box 1363, Folder 5)
  - 1980-Los Angeles, CA [file 11/19], Series 1 (Box 1364, Folder 1)
  - 1980-Los Angeles, CA [file 12/19], Series 1 (Box 1364, Folder 2)
  - 1980-Los Angeles, CA [file 13/19], Series 1 (Box 1364, Folder 3)
  - 1980-Los Angeles, CA [file 14/19], Series 1 (Box 1364, Folder 4)
  - 1980-Los Angeles, CA [file 15/19], Series 1 (Box 1364, Folder 5)
  - 1980-Los Angeles, CA [file 16/19], Series 1 (Box 1365, Folder 1)
  - 1980-Los Angeles, CA [file 17/19], Series 1 (Box 1365, Folder 2)
  - 1980-Los Angeles, CA [file 18/19], Series 1 (Box 1365, Folder 3)
  - 1980-Los Angeles, CA [file 19/19], Series 1 (Box 1365, Folder 4)
  - 1980-Los Angeles, CA-Host Committee Manual, Series 1 (Box 1365, Folder 5)
  - 1980-Los Angeles, CA-OCCM Budget, 1979-1980; Series 1 (Box 1365, Folder 6)
  - 1980-Los Angeles, CA-Presidential Visit, Series 1 (Box 1366, Folder 1)
  - 1980-Los Angeles, CA-Program, Series 1 (Box 1366, Folder 2)
  - 1981-Minneapolis, MN [file 1/13], Series 1 (Box 1366, Folder 3)
  - 1981-Minneapolis, MN [file 2/13], Series 1 (Box 1366, Folder 4)
  - 1981-Minneapolis, MN [file 3/13], Series 1 (Box 1366, Folder 5)
  - 1981-Minneapolis, MN [file 4/13], Series 1 (Box 1366, Folder 6)
  - 1981-Minneapolis, MN [file 5/13], Series 1 (Box 1367, Folder 1)
  - 1981-Minneapolis, MN [file 6/13], Series 1 (Box 1367, Folder 2)
  - 1981-Minneapolis, MN [file 7/13], Series 1 (Box 1367, Folder 3)
  - 1981-Minneapolis, MN [file 8/13], Series 1 (Box 1367, Folder 4)
  - 1981-Minneapolis, MN [file 9/13], Series 1 (Box 1367, Folder 5)
  - 1981-Minneapolis, MN [file 10/13], Series 1 (Box 1368, Folder 1)
  - 1981-Minneapolis, MN [file 11/13], Series 1 (Box 1368, Folder 2)
  - 1981-Minneapolis, MN [file 12/13], Series 1 (Box 1368, Folder 3)
  - 1981-Minneapolis, MN [file 13/13], Series 1 (Box 1368, Folder 4)
  - 1981-Minneapolis, MN-Host Committee Manual, Series 1 (Box 1368, Folder 5)
  - 1981-Minneapolis, MN-Programs, Series 1 (Box 1368, Folder 6)
  - 1982-Los Angeles, CA [file 1/12], Series 1 (Box 1369, Folder 1)
  - 1982-Los Angeles, CA [file 2/12], Series 1 (Box 1369, Folder 2)
  - 1982-Los Angeles, CA [file 3/12], Series 1 (Box 1369, Folder 3)
  - 1982-Los Angeles, CA [file 4/12], Series 1 (Box 1369, Folder 4)
  - 1982-Los Angeles, CA [file 5/12], Series 1 (Box 1370, Folder 1)
  - 1982-Los Angeles, CA [file 6/12], Series 1 (Box 1370, Folder 2)
  - 1982-Los Angeles, CA [file 7/12], Series 1 (Box 1370, Folder 3)
  - 1982-Los Angeles, CA [file 8/12], Series 1 (Box 1370, Folder 4)
  - 1982-Los Angeles, CA [file 9/12], Series 1 (Box 1370, Folder 5)
  - 1982-Los Angeles, CA [file 10/12], Series 1 (Box 1371, Folder 1)
  - 1982-Los Angeles, CA [file 11/12], Series 1 (Box 1371, Folder 2)
  - 1982-Los Angeles, CA [file 12/12], Series 1 (Box 1371, Folder 3)
  - 1982-Los Angeles, CA-Host Committee Manual, Series 1 (Box 1371, Folder 4)
  - 1982-Los Angeles, CA-Program, Series 1 (Box 1371, Folder 5)
  - 1983-Philadelphia, PA [file 1/9], Series 1 (Box 1371, Folder 6)
  - 1983-Philadelphia, PA [file 2/9], Series 1 (Box 1372, Folder 1)
  - 1983-Philadelphia, PA [file 3/9], Series 1 (Box 1372, Folder 2)
  - 1983-Philadelphia, PA [file 4/9], Series 1 (Box 1372, Folder 3)
  - 1983-Philadelphia, PA [file 5/9], Series 1 (Box 1372, Folder 4)
  - 1983-Philadelphia, PA [file 6/9], Series 1 (Box 1372, Folder 5)
  - 1983-Philadelphia, PA [file 7/9], Series 1 (Box 1373, Folder 1)
  - 1983-Philadelphia, PA [file 8/9], Series 1 (Box 1373, Folder 2)
  - 1983-Philadelphia, PA [file 9/9], Series 1 (Box 1373, Folder 3)
  - 1983-Philadelphia, PA-Host Committee Manual, Series 1 (Box 1373, Folder 4)
  - 1983-Philadelphia, PA-Program, Series 1 (Box 1373, Folder 5)
  - 1983 - School As a Concept, Not a Place - A Decade of Transition, 1973; Series 1 (Box 4110, Folder 14)
  - "1983: School As a Concept, Not a Place." A Decade of Transition: Highlights of the 1973 Critical Issues Conference, series 1 (Box 4418, Folder 19)
  - 1984-Minneapolis, MN-Band Opening Ceremony, Series 1 (Box 1373, Folder 6)
  - 1984-Minneapolis, MN-Budget, Series 1 (Box 1373, Folder 7)
  - 1984-Minneapolis, MN-Busing, Series 1 (Box 1373, Folder 8)
  - 1984-Minneapolis, MN-Camping, Series 1 (Box 1374, Folder 1)
  - 1984-Minneapolis, MN-Candidates, Series 1 (Box 1374, Folder 2)
  - 1984-Minneapolis, MN-Candidates Election, 1983-1984; Series 1 (Box 1374, Folder 3)
  - 1984-Minneapolis, MN-Car Rental, Series 1 (Box 1374, Folder 4)
  - 1984-Minneapolis, MN-Caucus Schedule, Series 1 (Box 1374, Folder 5)
  - 1984-Minneapolis, MN-Caucuses/Minority, Series 1 (Box 1374, Folder 6)
  - 1984-Minneapolis, MN-Caucuses-State, Series 1 (Box 1374, Folder 7)
  - 1984-Minneapolis, MN-Child Care, Series 1 (Box 1374, Folder 8)
  - 1984-Minneapolis, MN-Convention Bureau-Correspondence, 1985; Series 1 (Box 1374, Folder 9)